TUSHAR DAS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+91-7209748142

tushardas@wandererdroid.in

in @tshrds

profile.wandererdroid.in

Pengaluru

PROFILE

As a back-end engineer, Tushar specializes in building end-to-end applications and has around 8 years of relevant experience in IT.

He has worked with product teams catering to versatile customers ranging from Pharmaceuticals, Consumer Staple, HRMS, Tech-Ed and BFSI.

Tushar is a design-minded developer with good communication, interpersonal and problem-solving abilities, and likes to add value to the team to help boost Companies' data management efficiency.

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science and Technology from West Bengal University of Technology (2011 -2015)

EXPERTISE

Languages:

- Java/J2EE
- AngularJS1
- Python

Databases:

- RDBMS
- MongoDB
- Neo4J
- Snowflake
- Parquet/Delta Table

Frameworks:

- Spring MVC & Hibernate
- Spring Boot & JPA
- Python Whl
- Angular 1

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Calibo India Pvt Ltd

Apr 2021 - Present

LAZSA Platform

This project is a Integrated Business Digital Platform is a state-ofthe-art platform that accelerates the various stages of your digital innovation journey to help you deliver digital solutions quickly and in a unified manner.

- Domain: PPaaS
- Creating REST end-points to serve business requirement.
- Worked on NiFi Integration on various templates such as:
 Kafka to Snowflake, Kafka to Hadoop, FTP to MySQL, etc
- Introduced Metabase as a tech-stack (using docker container), which helps in visualization.
- Introduced Open-Refine as a tech-stack (using docker container), and added common transformations for easy data transform.
- Implemented S3 integration using AWS SDK.
- Implemented app creation and visualization in Qlik-Sense Technology.
- Was involved in creating DevOps pipeline using Jenkins CI/CD and deploying micro-services in EKS Clusters.
- Worked on python notebook to create a template to be used as AWS Kinesis Stream to S3 bucket pipeline.
- Introduced multi-object pipelines for AWS AppFlow.
- Worked on python wheel packages to be used in Databricks Notebook for integration.
- Worked on security fixes using sync and removed critical and high vulnerabilities from application

SENIOR ENGINEER

Altimetrik India Pvt Ltd

July 2015 - Mar 2021

1. Integrated Business Development Platform (BDP)

This project is a platform which integrates multiple technologies at a single platform for the developers. This follows the approach of all the pioneers building blocks: No Code, Low Code, and Pro Code. This will help customers to enhance their productivity. BDP is a platform, which provides multiple modules such as, techstack development, agile integrations, data integrations, with multiple dashboards and charts to visualize performance. It's a single platform where the user can Define, Design, Develop & Deploy.

- · Domain: PaaS
- Worked on Agile Integration using JIRA and Trello APIs.
- Worked on NiFi Integration: service endpoints to facilitate dataflow, design dataflow templates.
- Integrating AWS sdk for S3 integrations as a datasource for multiple technologies.
- Integrated Metabase and Qlik Sense as a data visualizations tools.

Data Tools:

- Databricks
- OpenRefine
- Nifi

Cloud Tools:

- AWS
- · Google Cloud Platform
- Azure

Development Tools:

- IntelliJ
- Eclipse
- PyCharm
- · Visual Studio Code

Dependency Manager:

- Gradle
- Maven

Visualization Tools:

- · Qlik Sense
- Metabase

Methodologies:

- Agile
- Waterfall

SOFT SKILLS

- Leadership
- Creativity
- Project Management
- Problem Solving

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recipient of multiple Inspire and Integrity Awards for consistent performance excellence
- Recipient of Gem Award at Calibo
- Visited Uruguay for business meet and to facilitate peer-programming with their team.
- Recipient of Spot Award at Altimetrik for exceptional performance in PLAYGROUND
- Winner of College
 Hackathon for building an
 enterprise application to
 meet the Organ Donation
 problem.

2. Playground

This project shapes and grooms talent, brings technology and engineering excellence, and provides us an opportunity to help our customers on their transformational initiatives. It also has a new approach to hiring high quality talent. It also included online test integration with third party services, creating amazon workspaces, undergoing various skill- based trainings to uplift the employees.

- Domain: HRMS
- Creating REST end-points to serve business requirement.
- Creating orchestrating layer end-point in nodeJS to interact UI with the back-end services.
- Integrating AWS sdk APIs to create workspaces and allow user to use the space in the aws directory.
- Integrating SDFC Sandbox APIs to create workspace for users.
- Eclipse CHE integration to enable users to use a cloud based workspace for development.

3. Platform-API E&M

This project is about creating various API's using Spring Boot and exposing each one of them as a different service. All the services are managed through a gateway channel, and the REST services are invoked via Swagger-UI template.

- · Domain: RestFull Services
- Integrating with phabricator git service for all git functionalities.
- Writing end services for spring cloud dataflow microservices.
- Building components with Spring-boot micro-services, Neo4j Graph DB
- Writing Junit Test cases.

4. Platform-WeaVon

This project is about creating a code generator in almost every possible language to atleast setup the base structure before creating an application. This will also support multiple databases as mysql, postgress, mongo, neo4j, etc. It will also include CI & CD process to directly integrate with github and deploy in a server for its use.

- Domain: Data Platform
- Writing application end services to integrate docker.
- Writing front-end view using template based architecture.
- Working on dynamic injection of templates using react and handlebar.
- Supported software integration and implemented maintenance enhancements to bolster product development cycle

5. AltiFin - Paysa

This project is about building a robust remittance application which will allow the fund transfer for the rural immigrant population at a low service charge.

- · Domain: BFSI
- Writing application end services to integrate with the Bank (initially RBL Bank, later switched to Axis Bank) APIs.
- Writing application end services to create file-uploader and other CRUD related services.
- Creating front end Angular design application to call and receive REST responses.